<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="American">All Diplomatic Policy slots in the current government are converted to Wildcard slots. +1 Diplomatic Favor per turn for each Wildcard slot in the current government.</string>
    <string name="TeddyRoosevelt">Tiles with Breathtaking Appeal gain +2 Science when adjacent to a Natural Wonder or Mountain, and +2 Culture when adjacent to a Wonder or Woods. +1 Appeal in all tiles in cities with a National Park.</string>
    <string name="Arabian">Automatically receives the final Great Prophet when the next-to-last one is claimed (unless one has already been earned through other means). +1 Science per foreign city following Arabia`s Religion.</string>
    <string name="Saladin">The Worship building for Arabia`s Religion is 90% cheaper to purchase with Faith. Arabian cities with that building gain +10% Science, Faith, and Culture.</string>
    <string name="Australian">+3 Housing in coastal cities. Building a Pasture triggers a Culture Bomb, claiming surrounding tiles. Campus, Commercial Hub, Holy Site, and Theater Square districts gain +1 to their yields in tiles with Charming Appeal, and +3 with Breathtaking Appeal.</string>
    <string name="JohnCurtin">+100% Production in all cities for the next 10 turns after being declared war upon or liberating a city.</string>
    <string name="Aztec">Can spend Builder charges to complete 20% of a district`s Production cost.</string>
    <string name="Montezuma">Improved Luxury resources provide an Amenity to 2 extra cities. +1 Strength Combat for all units for each different improved Luxury resource in Aztec territory.</string>
    <string name="Brazilian">Rainforest tiles provide a +1 adjacency bonus for Campus, Commercial Hub, Holy Site, and Theater Square districts, and grant +1 Appeal to adjacent tiles, instead of the usual -1.</string>
    <string name="PedroII">Recruiting or patronizing a Great Person refunds 20% of their point cost.</string>
    <string name="Canadian">Cannot declare Surprise Wars or war on city-states. Surprise Wars cannot be declared on Canada. For every 100 Tourism earned, gain 1 Diplomatic Favor. +100% Diplomatic Favor gained from successfully completing Emergencies and Competitions.</string>
    <string name="WilfridLaurier">Can build Farms on Tundra tiles, and on Tundra Hills tiles with Civil Engineering. Snow, Snow Hills, Tundra Hills, and Tundra tiles cost 50% less Gold Gold to purchase. On those types of tiles, Strategic Resources accumulate 100% faster, Farms and Camps receive +2 Food, and Mines and Lumber Mills receive +2 Production.</string>
    <string name="Chinese">Eurekas and Inspirations provide an extra 10% of the Science and Culture cost for researching technologies and civics. Completing a Wonder grants a Eureka and Inspiration from that Wonder`s era.</string>
    <string name="QinShiHuang">Builders receive an additional build charge. Can spend Builder charges to complete 15% of the Production cost for Ancient and Classical wonders. Unlocks Canals with Masonry instead of Steam Power.</string>
    <string name="Cree">Gains +1 Trade Route capacity and a free Trader with Pottery. Unclaimed tiles within three tiles of a Cree city come under Cree control when a Trader first moves into them.</string>
    <string name="Poundmaker">All Alliance types provide Shared Visibility. Trade Route grant +1 Food in the sending city and +1 Gold in the destination city per Camp or Pasture at the destination city.</string>
    <string name="Dutch">Rivers provide a +2 adjacency bonus for Campus, Theater Square, and Industrial Zone districts. Building a Harbor triggers a Culture Bomb, claiming surrounding tiles. +50% Production towards the Dam district and Flood Barrier building.</string>
    <string name="Wilhelmina">Domestic Trade Route provide +2 Loyalty per turn for the starting city. Trade Route sent to or received from a foreign civilization grant +2 Culture to the Netherlands.</string>
    <string name="Egyptian">+15% Production towards District and wonders built next to a river. Districts, improvements and units are immune to damage from floods.</string>
    <string name="Cleopatra">International Trade Route grant +4 Gold. Trade Routes sent to Egypt from other civilizations provide +2 Food for them and +2 Gold for Egypt. +100% Alliance Points from trading with allies.</string>
    <string name="English">Workshop of the World: Iron and Coal Mines accumulate +2 resources per turn. +100% Production towards Military Engineers. Military Engineers receive +2 charges. Buildings that provide additional yields when powered receive +4 of their respective yields. +20% Production towards Industrial Zone buildings. Harbor buildings grant +10 Strategic Resource stockpiles.</string>
    <string name="Victoria">The first city founded on each continent other than England`s home continent grants a free melee unit in that city and +1 Trade Route capacity. Building a Royal Navy Dockyard grants a free naval unit. Gains the Redcoat unique unit with Military Science.</string>
    <string name="EleanorofAquitaine">Each Great Work in her cities causes foreign cities within 9 tiles to lose 1 Loyalty per turn. Any foreign city that leaves its civilization due to loss of Loyalty and is receiving the most Loyalty pressure from Eleanor instantly joins her empire, instead of becoming a Free City.</string>
    <string name="French">+20% Production towards Medieval, Renaissance and Industrial Era Wonders. Double Tourism from Wonders of any Era.</string>
    <string name="CatherinedeMedici">+1 level of Diplomatic Visibility with every encountered civilization. Receives a free Spy (and extra Spy capacity) with Castles. All Spies start as Agents with a free promotion.</string>
    <string name="Georgian">Dedications chosen at the beginning of a Golden Age or Heroic Age also grant their Normal Age bonuses towards improving Era Score, in addition to their regular bonuses. +50% Production towards walls. Dramatic Ages only: While in a Golden Age, gain an additional Wildcard policy slot in all Governments, and can use Dark Age policy cards. +50% Production towards walls.</string>
    <string name="Tamar">Gains Faith from combat victories equal to 50% of the Strength Combat of the defeated unit. Each Envoy sent to a city-state of Georgia`s majority Religion counts as two Envoys.</string>
    <string name="German">Each city can build one more specialty District District than the Citizen Population limit would normally allow.</string>
    <string name="FrederickBarbarossa">Gains an additional Military policy slot in all Governments. +7 Strength Combat Strength for all units when fighting city-states and their units.</string>
    <string name="Greek">Gains an additional Wildcard Slot policy slot in all Governments.</string>
    <string name="Pericles">+5% Culture per city-state Greece has Suzerainty over.</string>
    <string name="Gorgo">Killing a unit provides Culture equal to 50% of its Combat Strength. All units gain +1 Combat Strength for every active Military Policy card in the current government.</string>
    <string name="Hungarian">+50% Production for districts and buildings built across a river from a City Center.</string>
    <string name="MatthiasCorvinus">Levied city-state units gain +2 Movement  and +5 Combat Strength, and can be upgraded at a 75% discount in Gold and resources. Levying troops from a city-state grants 2 Envoy with that city-state. Gains the Black Army unique unit with Castles.</string>
    <string name="Incan">Citizens can work Mountain tiles. Mountain tiles provide +2 Production, increasing to +3 Production after reaching the Industrial Era, and +1 Food for each adjacent Terrace Farm.</string>
    <string name="Pachacuti">Domestic Trade Routes gain +1 Food for every Mountain tile in the origin city. Gains the Qhapaq Nan unique improvement with Foreign Trade.</string>
    <string name="Indian">Indian cities receive the Follower Beliefs of all religions with at least one follower in them, not just the majority religion, and gain +1 Amenity for each religion with at least one follower in them. +2 Spread Religion charges for Missionaries. +100% Religious pressure from Indian Trade Routes.</string>
    <string name="Gandhi">+5 Faith for each met civilization (including India) that has founded a Religion and is not at war. Enemies receive double war weariness from fighting against Gandhi.</string>
    <string name="Chandragupta">Can declare a War of Territorial Expansion with Military Training, instead of Mobilization. +2 Movement and +5 Combat Strength for all units for the next 10 turns after declaring a War of Territorial Expansion.</string>
    <string name="Indonesian">Coast and Lake tiles provide a +0.5 adjacency bonus for Holy Site, Campus, Industrial Zone, and Theater Square districts. Entertainment Complexes built adjacent to a Coast or Lake tile provide +1 Amenity.</string>
    <string name="Gitarja">May purchase naval units with Faith. Religious units pay no movement cost to embark or disembark. City Centers adjacent to Coast or Lake tiles gain +2 Faith.</string>
    <string name="Japanese">Districts receive a +1 adjacency bonus for each adjacent district, instead of +0.5.</string>
    <string name="HojoTokimune">+5 Combat Strength for land units and naval units fighting on coastal and shallow water tiles. Encampment, Holy Site and Theater Square districts are built in half the time. Districts, improvements and units are immune to damage from Hurricanes. +100% damage from Hurricanes in Japanese territory to civilizations at war with Japan.</string>
    <string name="Khmer">Cities with an Aqueduct receive +1 Amenity, and +1 Faith for every point of Citizen Population in the city. Farms receive +2 Food when adjacent to an Aqueduct, and +1 Faith when adjacent to a Holy Site.</string>
    <string name="JayavarmanVII">Holy Sites grant Food equal to their adjacency bonus, receive a +2 adjacency bonus from Rivers, grant +2 Housing if built next to a River, and trigger a Culture Bomb when built, claiming surrounding tiles.</string>
    <string name="Kongolese">Relics, Artifacts and Sculptures grant +2 Food, +2 Production, +1 Faith, and +4 Gold. The Palace has four extra slots for Great Works. +50% Great Artist, Great Musician, and Great Merchant points gained from all sources.</string>
    <string name="MvembaaNzinga">May not build Holy Sites or found a religion, but receives all the beliefs of any religion that has established itself as Kongo`s majority religion, not just the Follower beliefs. Building a Mbanza or Theater Square grants a free Apostle of the city`s majority religion.</string>
    <string name="Korean">Farms receive +1 Food and Mines receive +1 Science for each adjacent Seowon.</string>
    <string name="Seondeok">Cities with an established Governor receive +3% Culture and +3% Science for each promotion that Governor has.</string>
    <string name="Macedonian">Conquering a city grants a free Eureka for each Encampment and Campus district in the conquered city and a free Inspiration for each Holy Site and Theater Square district.</string>
    <string name="Alexander">Macedonian cities never incur war weariness. All military units heal completely when a city with a Wonder is captured. Gain the Hetairoi unique unit with Horseback Riding.</string>
    <string name="Malian">City Centers gain +1 Faith and +1 Food for every adjacent Desert and Desert Hills tile. Mines receive -1 Production and +4 Gold. May purchase Commercial Hub buildings with Faith. -30% Production towards buildings and units.</string>
    <string name="MansaMusa">International Trade Routes gain +1 Gold for every flat Desert tile in the sending city. Entering a Golden Age permanently grants +1 Trade Route capacity.</string>
    <string name="Maori">Starts with Sailing and Shipbuilding unlocked and the ability to enter Ocean tiles. +5 Combat Strength and +2 Movement for embarked units. Unimproved Woods and Rainforests grant +1 Production, increasing to +2 Production with Mercantilism and +3 Production with Conservation. +1 Food from Fishing Boats. Building a Fishing Boat triggers a Culture Bomb, claiming surrounding tiles. Resources cannot be harvested. Great Writers cannot be earned.</string>
    <string name="Kupe">Starts the game in the Ocean. +2 Science and +2 Culture per turn before the first city is settled. The first settled city receives a free Builder and +1 Citizen Population. The Palace grants +3 Housing and +1 Amenity.</string>
    <string name="Mapuche">Cities with an established Governor gain +5% Culture, +5% Production, and +10% combat experience towards all units trained in the city. These numbers are tripled in cities not founded by the Mapuche. All cities within 9 tiles of a city with your Governor gain +4 Loyalty per turn towards your civilization.</string>
    <string name="Lautaro">+10 Combat Strength when fighting civilizations that are in a Golden or Heroic Age, or Free Cities. Defeating an enemy unit within the borders of an enemy city causes that city to lose 20 Loyalty, or 40 Loyalty if that civilization is in a Golden or Heroic Age.</string>
    <string name="Mongolian">Sending a Trade Route immediately creates a Trading Post in the destination city, instead of when the Trade Route is completed. Gains an extra level of Diplomatic Visibility with civilizations that have a Mongolian Trading Post. +6 Combat Strength for all units for each level of Diplomatic Visibility Mongolia has over the other civilization, instead of the usual +3 Combat Strength.</string>
    <string name="GenghisKhan">Cavalry class units gain +3 Combat Strength and have a chance to capture defeated cavalry class enemy units.</string>
    <string name="Norwegian">Can enter Ocean tiles with Shipbuilding, instead of Cartography. All units pay no Movement cost to embark or disembark. Naval melee units can heal in neutral territory.</string>
    <string name="HaraldHardrada">+50% Production toward naval melee units. Naval melee units gain the ability to perform coastal raids. Pillaging and coastal raiding grant Science, in addition to Gold, for Mines, and Culture, in addition to Faith, for Quarries, Pastures, Plantations, and Camps. Gains the Viking Longship unique unit with Sailing.</string>
    <string name="Nubian">+30% Production toward Ranged units. Ranged units gain +50% combat experience. +1 Production Production for Mines over strategic resources, and +2 Gold for Mines over bonus and luxury resources.</string>
    <string name="Amanitore">+20% Production towards Districts, increasing to +40% Production if there is a Nubian Pyramid adjacent to the City Center.</string>
    <string name="Ottoman">+50% Production toward Siege units. Siege units gain +5 Combat Strength against defensible Districts. Conquering a city doesn`t cause that city to lose Citizen Population. +1 Amenity and +4 Loyalty per turn for cities not founded by the Ottomans.</string>
    <string name="Suleiman">Has access to a unique Governor, Ibrahim, the Grand Vizier. Gains the Janissary unique unit and 1 Governor title with Gunpowder.</string>
    <string name="Persian">Gains +1 Trade Route capacity with Political Philosophy. Domestic Trade Routes provide +2 Gold and +1 Culture. Roads built inside Persian territory are one level more advanced than usual.</string>
    <string name="Cyrus">+2 Movement for all units for the next 10 turns after declaring a Surprise War. Declaring a Surprise War only counts as a Formal War for the purpose of Grievances and war weariness. Occupied cities have no penalties to their yields. +5 Loyalty per turn in occupied cities with a garrisoned unit.</string>
    <string name="Phoenician">Starts with the Eureka for Writing. Coastal cities founded by Phoenicia and in the same continent as their Capital always have full Loyalty. Settlers receive +2 Movement and Sight while embarked, and pay no Movement costs to embark or disembark.</string>
    <string name="Dido">Cities with a Cothon gain the unique Move Capital project, which moves the Phoenician Capital to that city. Gains +1 Trade Route capacity after building the Government Plaza or any Government Plaza building. +50% Production towards Districts in the city with the Government Plaza.</string>
    <string name="Polish">Building an Encampment or Fort triggers a Culture Bomb, claiming surrounding tiles. One Military policy slot in all governments is converted into a Wildcard policy slot.</string>
    <string name="Jadwiga">Taking territory from a foreign city with a Culture Bomb converts it to Poland`s religion. Relics grant +4 Gold, +2 Culture and +2 Faith. Holy Sites receive a +1 adjacency bonus from districts, instead of +0.5.</string>
    <string name="Roman">Founded or conquered cities start with a Trading Post Trading Post and, if within Trade Route range of the Capital, a road to it. Trade Routes generate +1 additional Gold from Roman Trading Posts they pass through.</string>
    <string name="Trajan">All founded cities start with a free building in the City Center. (A Monument if the game is started in the Ancient Era)</string>
    <string name="Russian">Founded cities start with five additional tiles. Tundra tiles provide +1 Faith and +1 Production, in addition to their usual yields. Districts, improvements and units are immune to damage from Blizzards. +100% damage from Blizzards inside Russian territory to civilizations at war with Russia.</string>
    <string name="Peter">Trade Routes to more advanced civilizations grant Russia +1 Science for every three technologies that civilization is ahead of them, and +1 Culture for every three civics.</string>
    <string name="Scottish">Happy cities gain +5% Science and +5% Production, and generate +1 Great Scientist points in their Campuses and +1 Great Engineer points in their Industrial Zones. Ecstatic cities double these bonuses.</string>
    <string name="RoberttheBruce">Can declare a War of Liberation with Defensive Tactics, instead of Diplomatic Service. +100% Production in all cities and +2 Movement for all units for the next 10 turns after declaring a War of Liberation.</string>
    <string name="Scythian">Building a light cavalry unit or Saka Horse Archer grants a free second copy of that unit.</string>
    <string name="Tomyris">+5 Combat Strength for all units when attacking wounded units. Units heal up to 30 hit points after killing an enemy unit.</string>
    <string name="Spanish">May form Fleets and Armadas with Mercantilism, instead of Nationalism and Mobilization. Trade Routes receive +3 Gold, +2 Faith and +1 Production. Trade Routes between multiple continents receive triple these numbers. Cities not on your original Capital`s continent receive +25% Production towards Districts and a Builder when founded.</string>
    <string name="PhilipII">Inquisitors can Remove Heresy one extra time and remove 100% of the presence of other religions. +5 Combat Strength for military and religious units against civilizations following other religions.</string>
    <string name="Sumerian">Capturing a Barbarian Outpost also grants a Tribal Village reward. Levying city-state units costs 50% less Gold.</string>
    <string name="Gilgamesh">May declare war on any civilization at war with an ally without warmonger penalties. When at war with a common enemy, Sumerian and allied units share pillage rewards and combat experience if within 5 tiles of each other. Earn Alliance Points per-turn if both civilizations are at war with the same foe. When fighting a common enemy, Gilgamesh and his allies share a +5 Combat Strength bonus.</string>
    <string name="Swedish">+50 Diplomatic Favor upon recruiting a Great Person. +1 Great Engineer points from Factories and +1 Great Scientist points from Universities. Sweden`s presence in the game adds three unique World Congress competitions in the Industrial Era.</string>
    <string name="Kristina">Buildings with at least three Great Work slots and wonders with at least two Great Work slots are automatically themed when all slots are filled. Gains the Queen`s Bibliotheque unique building in the Government Plaza.</string>
    <string name="Zulu">Capturing a city will upgrade the conquering unit into a Corps or Army, if the necessary civics are unlocked. +3 Loyalty per turn to cities with a garrisoned unit, increasing to +5 if the garrisoned unit is a Corps or Army.</string>
    <string name="Shaka">May form Corps with Mercenaries, instead of Nationalism, and Armies with Nationalism, instead of Mobilization. Corps and Armies gain an additional +5 Combat Strength.</string>
</resources>